
<project>

<projectID>22</projectID>

<projectDescription>
The data source contains data related to college admissions. Key attributes that would be reviewed in the admittance of a student into a university are included in this dataset, such as GRE Score, TOEFL Score,  etc.
As these attributes control admittance, the following research applies statistical theory to determine which attributes have a significant relationship with admittance into the university.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  The data set has an individual ID number, attributes that effect admittance, and a percent chance of admittance into the university.

  Serial.No: This is the unique identifier within the dataset. Each application to a school has its’ own Serial Number ID.

  GRE.Score: This is the standardized test (GRE) score for the corresponding application.

  TOEFL.Score: This is the international standardized test (TOEFL) score for the corresponding application.

  University.Rating: This is rating is related to the prestige of the university an applicant is seeking admission.

  SOP: Statement of Purpose Rating is a score between 1-5 (5 is strongest), this is the rating for a self-written letter included in university application.

  LOR: Letter of Recommendation Rating is a score between 1-5 (5 is strongest), this is rating the strength of the recommendation for the corresponding application.

  CGPA: Undergraduate university GPA on a scale of 1-10, 10 being the highest (best grades).

  Research: Binary variable relating to whether the applicant has performed research (1 = has performed research)

  Chance.of.Admit: Percent chance of applicant admission.
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>

</dataSource>



<researchQuestion>
  Identify which of the continuous variables has the most significant relationship with admission.

  GRE is a prominent factor in college admissions and will be evaluated on its’ own using Simple Linear Regression.

  GRE, TOEFL and CGPA will then be used together in multiple linear regression.

  Alpha level = .05
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
  There is significant evidence that the GRE effects the chance of admittance into University. Based on the model to determine whether GRE has an effect on admittance, a p-value of 2.2e-16 was observed. This is the probability of occurrence given that GRE does not have an effect on admittance.
  Multiple Linear Regression displays that when accounted for together, GRE, TOEFL, GPA all impact admittance. Performance of t-test on the model including these variables shows that GPA has a large t-value (16.003), meaning one unit increase of GPA has the most significant relationship with admittance if other variables are held constant.
</conclusion>

<class>
MLR
</class>

<fields>
 <field>9</field>
 <field>2</field>
 <field>3</field>
 <field>7</field>
</fields>

</project>
