
<project>

<projectID>35</projectID>

<projectDescription>
  We are interested in understanding the association of engine displacement, horse power, weight and acceleration of a car and its corresponding fuel consumption.
  To understand this better, we analyzed a dataset that contains fuel consumption in miles per gallon in terms of the other attributes.
  The hypothesis is that when engine displacement, horse power and weight are increased and acceleration decreased, the fuel consumption increases.
  In other words, we want to verify if these attributes are significant predictors of the car fuel consumption.
  In order to answer our research question, we will do a multiple linear regression analysis and run a F- Test for it.
  We will also analyze the plots generated by the model.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  Data set was obtained from: https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/auto-mpg
  The data concerns city-cycle fuel consumption in miles per gallon, to be predicted in terms of 3 multivalued discrete and 5 continuous attributes. For this research, I removed the multi-valued discrete attributes and the string attribute and kept only the continuous ones.
  Number of Instances: 398
  Number of Attributes: 9 including the class attribute Attribute Information:
  1. mpg: continuous
  2. cylinders: multi-valued discrete [Removed from data set] 3. displacement: continuous
  4. horsepower: continuous
  5. weight: continuous
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>
https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/auto-mpg
</dataSource>

<researchQuestion>
Are engine displacement, horse power, weight and acceleration of a car when considered together significant predictors of corresponding fuel consumption?
</researchQuestion>


<conclusion>
  According to the model and the data, there is evidence of a significant linear association between fuel consumption and engine displacement, horsepower, weight and acceleration.
  In other words, engine displacement, horsepower, weight and acceleration can be used to predict the fuel consumption.
</conclusion>

<class>
MLR
</class>

</project>
