
<project>

<projectID>62</projectID>

<projectDescription>
The World Meteorological Organization has collected data of residents in hurricane-prone areas.
The subject dataset includes collected data of U.S. East Coast residents when Hurricane Irma hit, along with whether or not each individual in the dataset survived the hurricane.
The WMO is looking for patterns in the data to help predict who has the best chance of surviving a hurricane.
</projectDescription>

<dataSource>
The dataset includes data on demographics (e.g. age, gender, salary) and personal preferences of each (e.g. favorite TV show, color, and superhero).
The dataset can be found at https://www.kaggle.com/rahulsathyajit/wmo-hurricane-survival-dataset
</dataSource>

<dataDescription>
  We am only using the following fields from the original dataset:

  DOB: Data of Birth
  M_STATUS: Marital Status
  SALARY: Salary
  EDU_DATA: Education Level
  EMP_DATA: Employment Status
  REL_ORIEN: Religious Status (Believer, Agnostic, or Atheist)
  GENDER: Male or Female
  ENDU_LEVEL: Rating of the individuals rating (units were not given)
  DIST_FRM_COAST: Distance the individual lives from the coast (in km)
  ALCOHOL: Preferred alcoholic beverage
  Class: x = “will survive”; y = “will not survive”

  Before loading the data, we added an Age field to use instead of DOB. This is the individuals age as an integer number of years.

  For cleanup, we moved from the provided factor fields to dummy variables. We also removed any rows with at least one blank input.
</dataDescription>

<researchQuestion>
  1.	Is “Age” a good predictor for survival?
  2.	What is the risk difference between Married and Unmarried individuals?
  3.	Are “Age” and “CloseToCoast” together good predictors for survival?
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
  1.	We do not have significant evidence at α=0.05 that “Age” is a good predictor for survival (p = 0.614); c-statistic = 0.5, meaning that age is no better than selecting at random.
  2.	We do not have significant evidence at α=0.05 that there is a risk difference between married and unmarried individuals.
</conclusion>

<class>
Logistic Regression
</class>

</project>
