
<project>

<projectID>5</projectID>

<projectDescription>
  The Exoplanet Exploration Program Office is supporting work to compile a list of nearby stars and their properties for future mission planning. Dataset is from the NASA Exoplanet Archive.
  Analysis will be finding if there is or not an association regarding star distance, spectral type, stellar luminosity, and degrees/temperature.
  Breakdown of the research questions will be as below.
  1.	Is there correlation between distance and luminosity or between degrees/temperature and luminosity?
  2.	Significant pairwise analysis will be used to do a SLR (F and T test).
  3.	All variables will be used for a MLR.
  4.	One way ANOVA will be done to compare means of two most significant variables.
  5.	Multiple logistic regression will be analyzed to summarize the model.

</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  Cleanup performed: removed columns not relevant for this analysis, kept the ones of interest. Description of each variable is below.
  1.	Star_name: Stellar name most commonly used
  2.	Decimal_degrees: Declination of the planetary system in decimal degrees
  3.	Star_dist: Distance to the planetary system in units of parsecs
  4.	St_spttype: Classification of the star based on their spectral characteristics following the Morgan-Keenan system. This was kept in order to segment the stars into groups, but upon closer review they have too many groups to categorize for aov.
  5.	St_lum: Amount of energy emitted by a star per unit time, measured in units of solar luminosities. The bolometric corrections are derived from V-K or B-V colors
  Stars that did not have data on record for luminosity were removed for this analysis, leaving 315 stars in total. Columns were formatted to 2 decimal places for standardization.
  Functions were used to get an overview of the data prior to analysis and models: summary, boxplot, and histogram.
</dataDescription>


<dataSource>

</dataSource>

<researchQuestion>
  Given star distance and luminosity have a linear positive relationship, will conduct pairwise tests as well as SLR, MLR, and later ANCOVA.
  Will compare significance of different models in regards to these variables in particular star distance and star luminosity controlling for degrees/temperature and not controlling.
  Assumption:
  Will not be removing outliers or influence points in this analysis. We will simply locate them as this is a “as is” analysis of the dataset, intended as a first iteration.
  A second iteration analysis on this dataset could be performed based on this initial analysis.
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
  Highlighting items based on each section
  1.	Can conclude distance and luminosity are more correlated than distance and temperature.
  2.	Used distance as response variable and luminosity as the explanatory variable.
  This test allowed to quantify relationship between the two variables resulting in an approximate equation of y= 16.845+0.026x.
  The formal H0 was B1 = 0 meaning no linear relationship and HA B1≠0 which would mean there is a linear relationship.
  The H0 was rejected at 0.05 level given significant p value.
  Visually there was a positive linear relationship observed from plots. As predicted degrees and luminosity returned a cluster plot given their lack of correlation.
  3.	Results for MLR gave an equation of y= 16.842+ 0.026 x_lum + -0.003 x_deg resulting in a significant p value for luminosity and a non-significant p value for degrees.
  F statistic was 8.575 with a small pvalue for overall test of 0.00023.
  4.	Goal of ANOVA was to compare means against groups. Two groups were created based on luminosity low for stars under 50 parsecs and high for 50 and above parsecs.
  The results were an F statistic of 27.99 which is the ratio of variability between groups to the variability between groups.
  When formally testing would reject H0 stating all means are the same given test resulted in 27.99 F> 3.87critical value.
  5.	Lastly in multiple logistic regression created a dummy variable defining success as distance proximity less than or equal to the mean of the data (17.37 units of parsecs).
  Results were both luminosity and decimal degrees were significant.
</conclusion>

<classes>
  <class>SLR</class>
  <class>MLR</class>
  <class>ANCOVA</class>
</classes>

<fields>
 <field>3</field>
 <field>5</field>
</fields>

</project>
