
<project>

<projectID>17</projectID>

<projectDescription>
  We want to compare the mean monthly return of the S-P 500 stock index (SPX) compared to the Dow Jones Industrial Average (Dow).
  The SPX has 500 individual constituents and the Dow has only 30.
  It would be much cheaper to replicate the Dow index compared to the SPX because you would need to buy less stocks which would save you a lot in commissions and fees.

  Can we get the same exposure and return characteristics by buying the cheaper index?
  Do the means differ over a long history?
  Do the indices have different ratios for large negative returns over the same time period?
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  We used Yahoo finance to grab the monthly returns of each index.
  We downloaded monthly index levels from January 2000 – December 2018.
  We then calculated the monthly return based off the index levels and was left with a return series from February 2000 – December 2018.
  We compiled the data into a single spreadsheet in the below format to make it easier to do comparisons.
  The first column is the date. The second column “Perc_Chg” is the monthly return of the index, expressed in decimal format.
  The last column is “Group” which is the index the return is associated with.
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>

</dataSource>


<researchQuestion>
Are the SPX and Dow monthly returns equivalent?
Can we use the smaller index to replicate a broader US index when it comes to equity investments?
</researchQuestion>


<conclusion>
  The S-P 500 and Dow Jones Industrial Average monthly returns are not statistically different.
  Although the mean SPX return 3.47% per month and the respective Dow return was 4.17% both data sets had relatively large standard deviations which resulted in no statistical difference in data sets.

  Furthermore, when looking at the proportion of months that had a negative return smaller than -7% there was again no statistical difference in the proportions.
</conclusion>

<class>
ANONA
</class>

</project>
