
<project>

<projectID>30</projectID>

<projectDescription>
The research scenario is to analyze the data of U.S. mortality rate and get answer for question regarding mortality rate and its relationship with other factors.
Since there is more than two groups in the dataset, one-way analysis of variance (ANOVA) is used to compare means across three groups.
In this research, the means of three race groups; black, white, and both races are compared. In this scenario, the variance is compared with in the race groups and between the race groups.
Linear regression is model is created to compare the variance by adjusting the variables.
Pairwise t test is done to find difference in variance  by adjusting and not adjusting the data set.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  This is dataset contains the U.S. mortality rate trend since 1900.
  It highlights the differences in age-adjusted death rates and life expectancy at birth by race and sex.
  Age-adjusted death rates (deaths per 100,000). It has five columns.
  They are Year, Race, Sex, Average life expectancy, and age adjusted death rate.
  The dataset contains the data from 1900 through 2014.
  The race has three groups; All race, black, and white. Similarly, there are three groups of sexes;
  they are both sexes, male, and female. Average life expectancy column contains the average life expectancy of person in particular year, race, and sex.
  Similarly, Age adjusted column contains the age adjusted death rate among 100,000 people that fall in particular year, race, and sex.
  The source of the data:
  https://catalog.data.gov/dataset/age-adjusted-death-rates-and-life-expectancy-at-birth-all-races-both-sexes-united-sta-1900
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>
https://catalog.data.gov/dataset/age-adjusted-death-rates-and-life-expectancy-at-birth-all-races-both-sexes-united-sta-1900
</dataSource>

<researchQuestion>
The main research questions is to find out if there is average life expectancy is vary by race group.
Is there any different in result by adjusting variables in the dataset?
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
F Statistics, which is ratio of between group variance and within group variance is higher in both cases.
So, we can say that variance between groups is higher in both cases.
We can conclude that, there is difference in mean between different races.
The mean life expectancy and death rate is not same in all races.
We can see same result in boxplot. The mean life expectancy and age adjusted death rate is higher among African American than White American.
</conclusion>

<class>
ANOVA
</class>

</project>
