
<project>

<projectID>33</projectID>

<projectDescription>
  Bike sharing systems are a new generation of traditional bike rentals where the whole process from membership, rental and return back has become automatic.
  Through these systems, user is able to easily rent a bike from a particular position and return back to another position.
  Currently, there are about over 500 bike-sharing programs around the world which are composed of over 500 thousand bicycles.
  Today, there exists great interest in these systems due to their important role in traffic, environmental and health issues.
  Apart from interesting real-world applications of bike sharing systems, the characteristics of data being generated by these systems make them attractive for the research.
  Opposed to other transport services such as bus or subway, the duration of travel, departure and arrival position is explicitly recorded in these systems.
  This feature turns bike sharing system into a virtual sensor network that can be used for sensing mobility in the city.
  Hence, it is expected that most of important events in the city could be detected via monitoring these data.

  This dataset contains the hourly and daily count of rental bikes between years 2011 and 2012 in Capital bikeshare system in Washington, DC with the corresponding weather and seasonal information.

  The main goal is to implement a simple linear regression model in order to predict and draw conclusions about the 1st year of operations of this bike sharing service.

  Reference: https://www.kaggle.com/marklvl/bike-sharing-dataset#Bike-Sharing-Dataset.zip
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  Bike-sharing rental process is highly correlated to the environmental and seasonal settings. For instance, weather conditions, precipitation, day of week, season, hour of the day, etc. can affect the rental behaviors. The core data set is related to  the two-year historical log corresponding to years 2011 and 2012 from Capital Bikeshare system, Washington D.C., USA

  - instant: record index
  	- dteday : date
  	- season : season (1:springer, 2:summer, 3:fall, 4:winter)
  	- yr : year (0: 2011, 1:2012)
  	- mnth : month ( 1 to 12)
  	- hr : hour (0 to 23)
  	- holiday : weather day is holiday or not (extracted from http://dchr.dc.gov/page/holiday-schedule)
  	- weekday : day of the week
  	- workingday : if day is neither weekend nor holiday is 1, otherwise is 0.
  	+ weathersit :
  		- 1: Clear, Few clouds, Partly cloudy, Partly cloudy
  		- 2: Mist + Cloudy, Mist + Broken clouds, Mist + Few clouds, Mist
  		- 3: Light Snow, Light Rain + Thunderstorm + Scattered clouds, Light Rain + Scattered clouds
  		- 4: Heavy Rain + Ice Pallets + Thunderstorm + Mist, Snow + Fog
  	- temp : Normalized temperature in Celsius. The values are divided to 41 (max)
  	- atemp: Normalized feeling temperature in Celsius. The values are divided to 50 (max)
  	- hum: Normalized humidity. The values are divided to 100 (max)
  	- windspeed: Normalized wind speed. The values are divided to 67 (max)
  	- casual: count of casual users
  	- registered: count of registered users
  	- cnt: count of total rental bikes including both casual and registered
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>
https://www.kaggle.com/marklvl/bike-sharing-dataset#Bike-Sharing-Dataset.zip
</dataSource>


<researchQuestion>
  -	Evaluate the effect of the season in the overall demand
  -	Evaluate the effect of the weather in the overall demand
  -	Evaluate the effect of the temperature in the overall demand
  -	Evaluate the effect of the humidity in the overall demand
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
  We have significant evidence at the alpha = 0.05 level that Season, Month, Holiday, temperature,
  Humidity is not equal to zero,  after controlling for other variables.
  That is, Humidity is a significant predictor of a bike rent after adjusting Season, Month, Holiday, temperature.
  (here, p less than 0.0001,p less than 0.0001 as calculated using software program)
</conclusion>

<class>
MLR
</class>

<fields>
 <field>16</field>
 <field>3</field>
 <field>5</field>
 <field>6</field>
 <field>9</field>
 <field>10</field>
 <field>12</field>
 <field>13</field>
</fields>

</project>
