<project>

<projectID>41</projectID>

<projectDescription>
No two graduate schools have the same admission standards.
Some favor test scores, while others prefer to see a student’s social impact or experience.
On the other hand, students may prefer more prestigious schools to lesser known schools.
However, before going through the process of filling out an application to certain schools, which can be laborious, students want to know how likely they are to get admitted.
The use of this research scenario is to provide prospective students a fitted probability of admittance to the graduate school.
In addition, it can be used for students in the future to determine what they need to prioritize to get into their dream school as well as similar schools.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>

The dataset is from UCLA and tracks 7 fields for 400 student applications to graduate school.
The fields include GRE scores, TOEFL scores, a University Rating score (1-5), Strength of Recommendations (1-5), GPA from Undergraduate school, whether or not a student has research experience (dummy variable) and the probability of admittance, as provided by the school.
The data set is clean and requires no work to clean up.
The dataset does lean toward higher scoring students on the GREs and the TOEFL, with the minimum score being 290 and 92 respectively, which is above average for both.
Thus, the model can only be applied to students in the range provided, meaning that this model does not hold for below average test score students.

</dataDescription>

<dataSource>

</dataSource>

<researchQuestion>
In what effect does GRE scores, research experience and undergraduate GPA have on the probability of graduate school admittance? In addition, are there different effects at different ratings of universities?
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
GRE score, undergraduate GPA and research are all significant factors into a higher probability of admittance of grad school.
If a student has to focus on one, undergraduate GPA is the most important, giving the chance of admittance a 15% boost for each point.
For every 10 points gained on the GRE, your odds of getting admitted increase by 2%.
Research has varying importance depending on the rating of the school you want to attend, as the data show that lowly rated schools barely care (0.5% impact for level 1) while prestigious care a whole lot more (7.7% impact for level 5).
</conclusion>

<class>
MLR
</class>

</project>
