
<project>

<projectID>39</projectID>

<projectDescription>
  We are interested in how the ratings affect the number of user downloads for the app in the Google Play Store.
  To understand it, we have to do multiple linear regression since my dependent variable (the number of user downloads) is continuous and can be impacted by other variables, such as paid/free.
  In other words, paid apps may have affected by ratings differently than the free ones in terms of the number of downloads.
  So, we have to control it. Otherwise, the omitted variable problem may occur.

  As we have to limit my data to 500, we will choose one of the categories, sports, as my subgroup.
  We will check whether higher rating levels for support related applications associated with the higher number of installments or not.
  By researching this, we aim to understand how people are affecting each other’s opinions while installing an application.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  Data set can be found: https://www.kaggle.com/lava18/google-play-store-apps/version/6
  They are 13 variables in the data set. Some of them  definitive string variables, so I use 7 of them.
  •	Category: Category the app belongs to (we used this category in order to subset data to sports.)
  •	Install: Number of user downloads/installs for the app (as when scraped – this is my dependent variable. Since it is based on large values, such as 100.000, 200.000, I take the log of the variable.)
  •	Rating: Overall user rating of the app (as when scraped - This is my independent variable)
  •	Reviews: Number of user reviews for the app (as when scraped – this is a control variable)
  •	Type: Paid or Free (this is a categorical control variable. If the app is paid, 1, otherwise, 0)
  •	Price: Price of the app (as when scraped - this is a control variable)
  •	Content Rating: Age group the app is targeted at - Children / Mature 21+ / Adult (this is a categorical control variable. For each variable I created a dummy variable.)
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>
https://www.kaggle.com/lava18/google-play-store-apps/version/6
</dataSource>

<researchQuestion>
Our research question is what are the effects on the number of installs for apps.
Is there a positive correlation between ratings and the number of installs for apps while controlling for the price, content rating and review numbers?
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
  If an application has higher rating values, this application is more likely to be installed more.
  The association between rating and the number of installments have a positive and significant relationship.
  The number of reviews also positively significant but its effect is smaller than that of rating.

  If an application is paid, the number of installments decrease significantly.
  If an application is free, people are more likely to install it.

  We expected that if an application is reachable by everyone, it would be more installed.
  However, the content rating categorical variables have no significant relation with the number of installments.

</conclusion>

<class>
MLR
</class>

<fields>
 <field>10</field>
 <field>4</field>
 <field>11</field>
 <field>8</field>
 <field>4</field>
</fields>

</project>
