
<project>

<projectID>26</projectID>

<projectDescription>
  We are interested in understanding differences in New York City school district student class room size.
  Since we limited our data set to 500, we will only review the number of students within certain departments.
  We want to understand if there are substantial differences between the class sizes dependent on the department a class is categorized in.

  We are using New York City school district data for Middle School and High School.
  The data set contains information on the number of students in various courses for grades 6-12.
  ICT courses (a category of the course section column) where there are more than 100 or less than 7 students are excluded.
  Similarly, for the self-contained course section with fewer than two students there is a filter.
  The data set is published by the New York Department of Education.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  Data set:
  https://data.cityofnewyork.us/Education/2018-2019-Class-Size-Pct-District-MSHS/4wgu-f3yf

  There are eight variables in the dataset. Each is identified and described below.

  1)	District
  a.	Numeric form
  b.	Provides a number per each district
  c.	There is no key to detail what number corresponds to what district
  2)	Grade Level
  a.	Describes what grade level students are in
  b.	There are two grade levels – HS Core and MS Core
  3)	Program Type
  a.	Describes the type of program student is enrolled in
  b.	There are two programs General Education and Self-Contained courses
  i.	No further explanation is given
  4)	Department
  a.	The department type details which department the class is within
  b.	There are four departments – English, Math, Science, and Social Studies
  5)	Class Size
  a.	Details the total number of students in one class
  6)	Number of Students
  a.	Details the total number of students enrolled in all classes of respective course
  7)	Number of Classes
  a.	Details the number of classes per a respective program type
  8)	% of Students within Grade
  a.	Describes the percentage of students within a grade
</dataDescription>


<dataSource>
https://data.cityofnewyork.us/Education/2018-2019-Class-Size-Pct-District-MSHS/4wgu-f3yf
</dataSource>


<researchQuestion>
  Our main research question is to understand the range of class sizes per department.
  We are hoping to understand if there are larger classroom sizes for certain departments which would warrant additional research.
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
From our analysis we see that there is no significant difference between the class sizes of the various departments.
</conclusion>

<class>
ANOVA
</class>

</project>
