
<project>

<projectID>2</projectID>

<projectDescription>
Features are computed from a digitized image of a fine needle aspirate (FNA) of a breast mass.
They describe the characteristics of the cell nuclei present in the image.
The target feature records the prognosis (malignant or benign).
We are interested in estimating the proportion of breast mass from the data collected that are benign just by the clump thickness.
We suspect that it may be 60% if clump thickness is greater than or equal to 6.
A random sample of 499 of breast mass is taken from the overall dataset.
Of those sampled, only 342 out of 499 are benign.
Formally test if the proportion of breast mass that is benign is different from 60% if clump thickness is greater than or equal to 6.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
The original data sample was produced by Dr. William H. Wolberg in 1992,
from his patient records at the University of Wisconsin Hospitals.
The dataset contained 699 samples with 458 benign and 241 malignant cases.
After looking at the overall data, the first attribute (Clump thickness) was selected ahead of all the other attribute
because it is a good predictor of the Class.
According to the research paper, clump thickness is used to assess if cells are mono-layered or multi-layered.
Benign cells tend to be grouped in mono-layers, while cancerous cells are often grouped in multi-layer.
[1] Due to the guidelines on this assignment, our data set was reduced to 499 records
with two attributes that is Clump thickness and the Class.
</dataDescription>


<dataSource>

</dataSource>

<researchQuestion>
Formally test if the proportion of breast mass that is benign is different from 60% if clump thickness is greater than or equal to 6.
</researchQuestion>


<conclusion>
We reject our assumption that the proportion of breast mass that is benign is 60% if the clump thickness is greater than or equal to 6.
In our sample, we are 95% sure that the proportion of breast mass that is benign is 68.54%
if the clump thickness is greater than or equal to 6 and not 60% as we initially thought.
</conclusion>

<class>
Two-Sample Tests for Proportions
</class>

</project>
