
<project>

<projectID>20</projectID>

<projectDescription>
The dataset contains the socio-economic info along with suicide rates.
Our goal is to evaluate if there is a relationship between the sum of suicide rate and the gdp per capita.
This will give us an indication if economic prosperity (or the lack thereof) is related to suicide rate.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
The dataset contains socio-economic info with suicide rates, by sex, age group, year, and by country.
For our research we are looking to evaluate the correlation between the per capita gdp and the suicide rate.
There are two suicide fields – suicide numbers, and suicides per 100k of population.
If we use the suicide numbers directly, the data will be biased based on the population size – bigger countries will obviously have more suicide numbers.
Hence we are going to use the suicides per 100 k of population, as this is standardized and will not be affected by the overall population of the country.
The per capita gdp per country, per year is constant.  So we are going to sum up the suicide data for each gdp per capita value.
Once we have this data, we will extract a random sample of 500 rows and perform our evaluations on it.
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>

</dataSource>


<researchQuestion>
Calculate the correlation coefficient between suicide rate and gdp per capita.
Plot a scatterplot graph, and check for any outliers.  If there are outliers, evaluate the effect of the outliers on the relationship.
Test if there is a linear relationship present between suicide rate and the gdp per capita, at alpha = 0.05.
State your conclusion.
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
  Summary of findings:
  1.	We find the correlation coefficient, both before (0.0012) and after removing the potential outliers (0.018), does NOT indicate a strong relationship between suicide rate and per capita GDP.
  2.	Considering H0 as the hypothesis which states that there is no linear relationship between suicide rate and per capita GDP, at 95% confidence level we are unable to reject H0 using a t test.

  Conclusion:
  At 95% confidence level we are unable to find a strong linear relationship between suicide rate and per capita GDP.
</conclusion>

<class>
Correlation Tests
</class>

</project>
