
<project>

<projectID>25</projectID>

<projectDescription>
  This data set belongs to transactions made in a retail store during Black Friday event.
  Using this data we are trying to extract the customer purchase behavior of various products.
  We are performing a regression test to predict the dependent or response variables purchase amount with various independent or explanatory variables gender, city stay in years, marital status, and age group.

  A sample of 500 observations were taken with quantitative variable Purchase Amount, and city stay in years.
  The Qualitative or categorical variables are gender, marital status, and age group.

  Correlation tests to find out the correlation between age and Purchase Amounts or years of stay and Purchase Amount
  Multiple Linear Regression Model: Used to find of relation between set of Explanatory variables and Response variable.
  Logistics Regression: It is based on linear relationships between the natural logarithm of the odds of an event and linear combination of explanatory variables.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
This data set belongs to transactions made in a retail store during Black Friday event.
Using this data we are trying to extract the customer purchase behavior of various products.
We are performing a regression test to predict the dependent or response variables purchase amount with various independent or explanatory variables gender, city stay in years, marital status, and age group.
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>

</dataSource>


<researchQuestion>
  Since there are one or more explanatory variables like Marital Status, Age Groups, Gender I would like to perform a logistic Regression by modeling relationship between independent variables and response variable Purchase Price.
  This will give us a good visibility to purchase behavior.
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
  In Multiple regression model we have evidence that there is linear association between Age and Purchase Amount after controlling years of City Stay.
  Likewise we don’t have evidence that is linear association between City Stay and Purchase amounts after controlling age of consumers.

  From Multiple Logistic Regression there evidence that there is association between Marital status and Purchase after controlling City stay in years.
  The is no evidence that there is association between city stay and Purchases.
</conclusion>

<class>
Logistic Regression
</class>

</project>
