
<project>

<projectID>11</projectID>

<projectDescription>
In resent years we have seen the increase in interest in the world of comics and the heroes.
The creation of new characters that will assimilate to the publics interests will likely create a steady revenue for a publishing or movie industry.
We look to find out if there is a correlation between the popularity of a character, with in the basis of the number of the abilities, gender and alliance.
We am going to look to find the most popular comic book characters from the Marvel Comics Universe and compare the number of abilities.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  We found the dataset in Kaggle and it is called “superhero set”, it contains two sets of data.
  One data set contains descriptive information about each of the characters gender, weight, height, descriptions and affiliations; the other dataset contains the abilities for each of the characters.
  In order to reduce the population, we tried to keep it to only the characters from the Marvel Comics Publisher.

  The dataset did not contain a ranking of the comic book characters based on popularity.
  We obtained datasets and added fields for the missing data.
  Also, we created a column for the total number of powers and the total abilities per category.
  We also substituted True/False values to 1/0 in order to be able to be added to get totals per column and row.

  The datasets can be found on the following link.
  https://www.kaggle.com/claudiodavi/superhero-set

  We also referenced the following link for a popularity listing:
  https://www.ranker.com/crowdranked-list/top-marvel-comics-superheroes
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>
https://www.kaggle.com/claudiodavi/superhero-set
</dataSource>


<researchQuestion>
We want to predict that the number of abilities, gender and affiliation will allow us to predict weather a character will be popular or not.
</researchQuestion>


<conclusion>

In conclusion, we was unable to find a relationship between number of abilities, gender and/or affiliation to the popularity of a character.

</conclusion>

<class>
ANOVA
</class>

</project>
