
<project>

<projectID>48</projectID>

<projectDescription>
The percent of a man’s body that is fat is matter of concern for health and fitness reasons.
However, the percentage of body fat is difficult and expensive to measure accurately.
According to HealthLine, the most accurate method for determining body fat percentage is with an MRI or computerized tomography (CT) scan which can cost as little as $474 or as high as $13259 with health insurance coverage.
The dataset “Bodyfat” offers correct percentage of bodyfat measurements along with a variety of easily to find measurements.
</projectDescription>

<dataDescription>
  Source: BYU Human Performance Research Center http://www.byu.edu/chhp/intro.html#lrc Director: Mark Ricard 116A RB, (801) 378-8958

  The dataset “Bodyfat” includes measurements of 250 men of various ages. Below is a list of the variables relevant to the research study and short description:

  Pct.BF- the percentage of body fat (measured with MRI/ CT)
  Age- the age of the individual
  Weight- the weight in pounds (lb) of the individual
  Height- the height in inches (in) of the individual
  Neck- the neck size in centimeters (cm) of the individual
  Chest- the chest size in centimeters (cm) of the individual
  Waist- the waist size in inches (in) of the individual
  Bicep- the bicep size in centimeters (cm) of the individual
  Forearm- the forearm size in centimeters (cm) of the individual
  BMI- the body mass index of the individual as calculated by the American Cancer Society
  WeightRange- a categorial variable with categories: Underweight, Normal, Overweight, Obese (ACS)
</dataDescription>

<dataSource>
http://www.byu.edu/chhp/intro.html#lrc
</dataSource>


<researchQuestion>
Given the high cost of measuring a person’s percentage of bodyfat, can one build a model to predict the percentage of bodyfat, with a high degree of accuracy, using more easily made measurements?
</researchQuestion>

<conclusion>
Simple Model: PercentageofBodyFat = -41.86 + 1.68Waist
Refined Model: PercentageofBodyFat = -36.56 + 2.48Waist - 11Weight -40Neck
The intent of this study was to find a cost-effective solution to calculating a person’s body fat percentage.
This solution would require building a predictive model using easily made measurements instead of an MRI or CT.
A simple model was used to assess which variable had the most predictive power.
I found that the Waist variable (a measure of an individual’s waist) was able to explain 65.26% of the variation in body fat percentage.
A refined model was then built to control for other factor such as, Weight and Neck size.
The refined model shown above was able to explain 70.26% of the variation in body fat percentage.
Overall, this model can predict a person’s percentage of body fat fairly accurately, given waist, weight, and neck size.
This model is a start to finding a cost-effective solution, perhaps a more effect model would include average daily caloric intake.
</conclusion>

<class>
SLR, MLR
</class>

</project>
